Guide to the Stanford University, Vice Provost for Academic Planning and Development, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Vice Provost for Academic Planning and Development, records
1981-1991
SC0484
Stanford University. Vice Provost for Academic Planning and Development.
10.5 Linear feet
These records were generated by Vice Provosts William M. Chace, 1986-88, and John D. Wirth, 1988-91, and pertain to Centennial Campaign fundraising, the Stanford Museum, academic programs, fellowships, overseas studies, and other matters.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1991.
Information about Access
Restricted access: for more information consult the University Archivist.
Description of the Collection
These records were generated by Vice Provosts William M. Chace, 1986-88, and John D. Wirth, 1988-91, and pertain to Centennial Campaign fundraising, the Stanford Museum, academic programs, fellowships, overseas studies, and other matters.
Access Terms
Chace, William M.; Chace, William M.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Curricula.;; Stanford University. Vice Provost for Academic Planning and Development.; Wirth, John D.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession 1991-143
  - Hum Bio Centennial Event (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Miscellaneous Centennial Reports] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Centennial Brainstorming (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Centennial Campaign: prospectuses and organization (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - President’s Centennial discussion meeting, 11/21/85 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Campaign: write-ups for each priority (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Centennial Campaign: endowment document (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Album: Nilan and Davis a Campaign Proposal (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Press and the Centennial Campaign (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Centennial Dress Rehearsal (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Faculty advocates during campaign (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Faculty recruitment for the Centennial (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - President’s Advisory Committee on Development and Planning (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - International Studies at Stanford / proposals for the Centennial Campaign (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Youth Development Center: Centennial Plans (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Facts – Centennial (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Centennial Long Range Plans (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meetings with Deans (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Midcourse Correction (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lagging featured undergraduate objectives (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Review 1, 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - DPC Deans 12/90 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Centennial events (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Centennial Campaign Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Kennedy/Mexico City (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mexican Fellowship Fund (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Centennial: Homestretch (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Campaign co-chairs (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Student Centennial Petition (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Centennial Professorships (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Near West reports (Box 3)
  - Stanford Campaign (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - [Assorted correspondence etc.] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - President’s Faculty Council on the Centennial Campaign (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chicago / Portland NCC (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - NCCs (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - National Centennial Campaign (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chicago NCC (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - NCC features / students (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - NCC 1990s (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mexico NCC (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - H & S - Centennial Review (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Faculty scholars program (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - DPC [Development Priorities Committee] forms (updated) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Earth Sciences (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Earth Sciences – 10 year plan (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Engineering (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - GSB (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Humanities & Sciences (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - DPC repositioning (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Faculty staff giving (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - [Miscellaneous on Alumni Fellows Program] (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Courses on demand for Alums (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Earthquake publications (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Earthquake and the Centennial (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Earthquake (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - FEMA (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Quad Renovation (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Department Chairpersons (conversations/searches) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Chace: Development activities in H&S 1982-85 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Relations with Henry Riggs, Development Office (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - DPC actions (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Development activities approved (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Joint retreat 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Proposal for National Language Center (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Library Prospectus (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Project (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - School of Education (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Packet on Stanford Institute for Manufacturing and Automation (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Prospectus: School of Engineering (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Various Prospectuses from the Schools and Library (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Brigitte Carnochan (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Endowed coachships: fundraising (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fundraising approval letters (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - DAPER, Riggs, Geiger (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fundraising: School of Medicine (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - H&S fundraising / Chace (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Principal, Major, Leadership Gifts (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Large Gift Volunteer Conference (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - [Miscellaneous fundraising materials] (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fundraising – goals (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fundraising – methods (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - President's Resource Group (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - President's Resource Group Rehearsal 10/29/85 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - A Survey of Residents of Palo Alto and Menlo Park, Office of Public Affairs, Stanford University, August 29, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers: Stanford, a Centennial Chronology and Stanford, A Centennial Celebration 1885-1985 [Times-Tribune] (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - [Miscellaneous unsorted materials] (Box 6, Folder 5-9)
  - Salary distribution 1985-86 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - General Policies (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Development proposals in the Fine Arts (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Dance at Stanford: proposals and correspondence (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - ACIS and Robert Street development activity (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Centennial Campaign: the Fine Arts (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Theater Advisory Group (Box 7)
  - Art Donors (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Committee for Outdoor Art (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - de Menil Museum (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Al Elsen (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Exedra Planning (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Museum: H & S (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Architect at Stanford (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Museum concepts (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Museums (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Museum - vision statement (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Museum option papers, Trustees 6/89 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Museum funding (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Art - current (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Trustee Museum Committee (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Museum Director Search, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Art Gallery (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Museum – Current (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Eitner “The Development of the Stanford Museum 1964-1988; The Stanford Museum, vols. XVI-XVII (Box 8)
  - John Eastman (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Museum renovation (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Anderson Collection (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Anderson Art Collection – EMW (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Anderson Art Collection (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - H & S Deans Report (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Santiago (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Undergrad Admissions - the brightest (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Theatre & Roble (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - McLuhan Chair (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Golden" writing program (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Robert Golden, San Diego (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Clint Smith (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Robert Keller (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Leonard Rieser (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - James Nagle (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Howard Morgens (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Morris Doyle (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Paul Basch (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Elizabeth Traugott (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Ray Bacchetti (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Nancy Bruno (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Claudio Gonzalez (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Heller & Drell (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Leon Campbell (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Susan Duggan (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Sue Jackson (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Gitta Meetings (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Linda Clever (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Faculty gains and losses (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Continuing Studies Program (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Earth Sciences (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Eberlee (Royal Institute) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Vice President areas (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hall of Fame (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Library (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Meyer Renovation (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Library Search (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Student teleconferencing proposals (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - School of Education Annual Fund (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - CNR Italy negotiations, 1987-91 – miscellaneous [Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche] (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - CNR current (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - CNR key documents (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Bob Byer - research guidelines (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - [miscellaneous Italy negotiations] (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Florence projects (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - CNR conference at Stanford (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - CNR – enquiries (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Min. Ruberti visit 11/3/89 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Italian projects, CNR, etc. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - CNR humanities / psych (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Italy trip 1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Rossi (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Trip to Italy 10/87 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Stanford/Italian Collaboration (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - CNR proposals (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Agreement – Italy and Stanford (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Cassesse (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Letter of intent (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Italy negotiations (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Italy negotiations (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Materials on the National Research Council of Italy (Box 11, Folder nf)
  - Italian dinner Nov. 39, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Australia, 1990-91 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Australia's proposals (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Enany (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Marbella Project (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Mexico: Debt for Equity (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Mexico teacher training (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Portuguese studies (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Portugal trip, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Portugal Conference – Wilson Center 1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Portugal Chair (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Amr Ermany / Bill Wraith (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - University in Spain (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Office of Development Long Range Planning Committee, 1989-90 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - SOAC (Senate Oversight Advisory Committee on the Centennial Campaign), 1988- (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - SOAC Senate reports (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - John Wirth road trips for the Campaign: Sacramento, Mexico, Canada, Palm Springs, Brazil, Spain, Denver, Los Angeles, San Diego, Orange County, Fresno, Santa Barbara, New York, San Jose (Box 13)
  - Humanities, Plight de (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Humanities Forum (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Humanities Institute Conference, Sept. 10-13, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Humanities Study Group (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Report: Assessment of Research-Doctorate Programs (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Legacies from H & S 1983 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Humanities and Sciences Council (Box 14, Folder 7-9)
  - Faculty and staff contributions (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Humanities executive program (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Humanities Center, 1980 - 85 (Box 15, Folder 1-11)
  - Humanities Center, 1985-86 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Humanities Center, 1986-87 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Humanities Center, 1987-88 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Teaching – H&S (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - John Cash – H&S (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - H&S fundraising (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Humanities and Sciences Council (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Monterey Institute of International Studies (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Monte Carlo IBM Conference (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - H&S Centennial 9/16/88 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Apple (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Blokker (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Bowen McCoy Gift (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - CL/MTL inheritance items (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Killefer (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Carlsen (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Connolly (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Robert Eliot King (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Meier - Lodato (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Liliore Green Rains II (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Future of S.U. Bookstore/Committee meetings (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Bookstore meeting notes (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Bookstore: licensing, marks & royalties (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - SLE [Structured Liberal Education] (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Residential Education Computer Network (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Research Academic Programs (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Undergraduate residence (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Freshmen writing (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Future of VTSS (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - VTSS negotiations (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - H & S graduate fellowships (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - GSB fellowships (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Undergraduate fellowships (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Repositioning (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Dean’s Council (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Dean’s Cabinet (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Stanford governance (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Table of organization (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Action plan for change (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Stanford cost cutting/overhead (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - John D. Wirth job 1990-91 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Staff: Sharon Dickow (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Institute for International Studies Jump Start (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Institute for International Studies vision drafts (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Institute for International Studies planning committee (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Shultz - Institute for International Studies vision (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Hewlett IIS Match (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Hewlett Foundation anniversary (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Hoover and Office of Development (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Hoover - Centennial links (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Undergraduate residence: planning and disc. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Summer sessions: Ad Hoc Committee (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Center for Economic Policy Research (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Meetings with Jim Rosse and Vice Provosts (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Committee on Libraries, 1986-87 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Senate Advisiory Committee: campaign ideas from faculty (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Development Priorities Committee and Green Folders Group Business, 1988-91 [unsorted] (Box 20)
  - Development Priorities Committee and Green Folders Group Business, 1988-91 [unsorted] (Box 21)